<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Yifei Ethan Zuo</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Yifei Ethan Zuo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 23:40:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Empirical Analysis of Attention Rotary Effect</title>
      <link>/posts/empirical-analysis-of-attention-rotary-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 23:40:55 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/empirical-analysis-of-attention-rotary-effect/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In long context sequence modeling, Language models tend to forget in the middle. This is a messy phenomenon related to the datasets and a systematic inductive-bias of the attention mechanism. It has been observed and leveraged in the acceleration of Transformer inference, as compressing the middle part of the sequence does not affect the performance much. But this is not a good thing to celebrate, as the model should be able to retrieve the middle part of the sequence according to the context, while they receive barely no attention from the model merely based on their position.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear Time Sequence Modeling Annotation</title>
      <link>/posts/linear-time-sequence-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 23:26:54 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/linear-time-sequence-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Have no time for this, flesh out in the future
Modeling dynamic system is the core topic in control theory. Analytical methods involve solving differential equations and require symbolic computation. In computer control, we seek to find computational models to solve the dynamic system. In SISO case, suppose that $x(t) \in \mathbb R^d$ is the state of the system at time $t$, $u(t) \in \mathbb R$ is the impulse and the response is $y(t) \in \mathbb R$.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
